<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personality on Nils Myszkowski, PhD</title>
    <link>/categories/personality/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personality on Nils Myszkowski, PhD</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/personality/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Individual Differences in Within-Person Variability in Personality Positively Predict Economic Gains and Satisfaction in Negotiations</title>
      <link>/publications/2022-03-17-individual-differences-in-within-person-variability-in-personality-positively-predict-economic-gains-and-satisfaction-in-negotiations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2022-03-17-individual-differences-in-within-person-variability-in-personality-positively-predict-economic-gains-and-satisfaction-in-negotiations/</guid>
      <description>What it&amp;rsquo;s about   In this paper, we study how within-person variability (the tendency of a person to vary in personality) predicts success in negotiations.
Abstract   Prior research on the value of personality traits for predicting negotiation outcomes is rather inconclusive. Building on prior research and in light of recent personality and negotiation theories, we discuss why the traditional approach to personality traits has had limited success and propose an alternative approach to predicting negotiation outcomes from personality assessments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the associations between personality and response speed trajectories in low-stakes intelligence tests</title>
      <link>/publications/2022-03-04-exploring-the-associations-between-personality-and-response-speed-trajectories-in-low-stakes-intelligence-tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2022-03-04-exploring-the-associations-between-personality-and-response-speed-trajectories-in-low-stakes-intelligence-tests/</guid>
      <description>What it&amp;rsquo;s about   In this paper, using Log-Normal Item-Response Theory models for response time data, we study how personality traits predict response speed trajectories in low-stakes reasoning tasks. We found that some traits are associated with increasing in speed vs. decreasing in speed, controlling for item effects.
Abstract   Previous research suggests a negative relationship between test taking speed and performance in mental ability testing, inviting researchers to explore the origin of individual differences in test taking speed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A forgotten antecedent of career adaptability: A study on the predictive role of within-person variability in personality</title>
      <link>/publications/2020-within-person-adaptability/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2020-within-person-adaptability/</guid>
      <description>What it&amp;rsquo;s about   In this paper, we study the relation between within-person variability in personality (the extent to which one changes in personality across situations) and career adaptability.
Abstract   Several studies have focused on stable personality traits as antecedents of career adaptability, but few have investigated more dynamic aspects of personality in relation to career adaptability. Recent theories on personality such as Whole Trait Theory (Fleeson, 2015) recognize that traits are often aroused in one situation but not in another (Allport, 1937), and that individuals are more or less flexible in responding to different situations.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
