<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My publications on Nils Myszkowski, PhD</title>
    <link>/publications/</link>
    <description>Recent content in My publications on Nils Myszkowski, PhD</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/publications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Individual Differences in Within-Person Variability in Personality Positively Predict Economic Gains and Satisfaction in Negotiations</title>
      <link>/publications/2022-03-17-individual-differences-in-within-person-variability-in-personality-positively-predict-economic-gains-and-satisfaction-in-negotiations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2022-03-17-individual-differences-in-within-person-variability-in-personality-positively-predict-economic-gains-and-satisfaction-in-negotiations/</guid>
      <description>What it&amp;rsquo;s about   In this paper, we study how within-person variability (the tendency of a person to vary in personality) predicts success in negotiations.
Abstract   Prior research on the value of personality traits for predicting negotiation outcomes is rather inconclusive. Building on prior research and in light of recent personality and negotiation theories, we discuss why the traditional approach to personality traits has had limited success and propose an alternative approach to predicting negotiation outcomes from personality assessments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the associations between personality and response speed trajectories in low-stakes intelligence tests</title>
      <link>/publications/2022-03-04-exploring-the-associations-between-personality-and-response-speed-trajectories-in-low-stakes-intelligence-tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2022-03-04-exploring-the-associations-between-personality-and-response-speed-trajectories-in-low-stakes-intelligence-tests/</guid>
      <description>What it&amp;rsquo;s about   In this paper, using Log-Normal Item-Response Theory models for response time data, we study how personality traits predict response speed trajectories in low-stakes reasoning tasks. We found that some traits are associated with increasing in speed vs. decreasing in speed, controlling for item effects.
Abstract   Previous research suggests a negative relationship between test taking speed and performance in mental ability testing, inviting researchers to explore the origin of individual differences in test taking speed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accounting for Variable Task Discrimination in Divergent Thinking Fluency Measurement – An Example of the Benefits of a 2-Parameter Poisson Counts Model and its Bifactor Extension Over the Rasch Poisson Counts Model</title>
      <link>/publications/2021-2ppcm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2021-2ppcm/</guid>
      <description>What it’s about In this paper, we introduce new psychometric models for count/fluency tasks (tasks in which individuals have to provide many instances). Notably, we extent the Rasch Poisson Counts Model (RPCM) to account for variable discrimination (2-Parameter Poisson Counts Model) and to account for local dependencies/nuisance factors (Bifactor 2-Parameter Poisson Counts Model).
 Abstract Fluency tasks are among the most common item formats for the assessment of certain cognitive abilities, such as verbal fluency or divergent thinking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Mokken Scale Analysis of the Last Series of the Standard Progressive Matrices (SPM-LS)</title>
      <link>/publications/2020-mokken/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2020-mokken/</guid>
      <description>What it’s about In this paper, I reanalyze a dataset for a special issue of Journal of Intelligence. The analysis uses the framework of Mokken Scale Analysis (MSA), which is a non-parametric approach to relations between item responses and attributes (i.e. Item-Response Theory).
 Abstract Raven’s Standard Progressive Matrices (Raven 1941) is a widely used 60-item long measure of general mental ability. It was recently suggested that, for situations where taking this test is too time consuming, a shorter version, comprised of only the last series of the Standard Progressive Matrices (Myszkowski and Storme 2018) could be used, while preserving satisfactory psychometric properties (Garcia-Garzon et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creativity and unethicality – A systematic review and meta-analysis</title>
      <link>/publications/2021-creativity-unethicality/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2021-creativity-unethicality/</guid>
      <description>What it’s about In this paper, we provide a meta-analysis of correlations between (un)ethical behavior and creativity, notably controlling for how the constructs were measured – which, as it turns out, is important when considering the heterogeneity of the findings.
 Abstract A growing line of research suggests that creativity and unethicality are intrinsically related to one another. However, the idea has been challenged both by theoretical arguments and by heterogeneous empirical findings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A forgotten antecedent of career adaptability: A study on the predictive role of within-person variability in personality</title>
      <link>/publications/2020-within-person-adaptability/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2020-within-person-adaptability/</guid>
      <description>What it&amp;rsquo;s about   In this paper, we study the relation between within-person variability in personality (the extent to which one changes in personality across situations) and career adaptability.
Abstract   Several studies have focused on stable personality traits as antecedents of career adaptability, but few have investigated more dynamic aspects of personality in relation to career adaptability. Recent theories on personality such as Whole Trait Theory (Fleeson, 2015) recognize that traits are often aroused in one situation but not in another (Allport, 1937), and that individuals are more or less flexible in responding to different situations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Same Test, Better Scores – Boosting the Reliability of Short Online Intelligence Recruitment Tests with Nested Logit Item Response Theory Models</title>
      <link>/publications/2019-same_test/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2019-same_test/</guid>
      <description>What it’s about In this paper, we propose to generalize the use of Nested Logit Models and implement its use for online personnel selection procedures that use reasoning tests with multiple choices (e.g., matrix-type tests). We find that using such models results in gains of reliability, especially at low ability levels.
 Abstract Assessing job applicants’ general mental ability online poses psychometric challenges due to the necessity of having brief but accurate tests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A snapshot of g? Binary and polytomous item-response theory investigations of the last series of the Standard Progressive Matrices (SPM-LS)</title>
      <link>/publications/2018-intelligence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/2018-intelligence/</guid>
      <description>What it’s about In this paper, we propose the use of the last series of the last series of the Standard Progressive Matrices (SPM-LS) as a viable snapshot measure of g. We provide an extensive Item-Response Theory (IRT) analysis of the instrument, based on the binary (pass/fail) and nominal (response categories) data.
 Abstract Raven’s progressive matrices (Raven, 1941) are extremely popular measures of general mental ability. However, their length may not suit every researcher’s or practitioner’s needs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
